# **Stephanie Viveros**

I am a motivated software engineer with a passion for learning and thirst for continuous self-improvement. My previous experience in customer service and leadership positions has rewarded me with strong leadership abilities and communication skills. I hope to utilize my foundation, motivation, and passion to benefit your company.

**Address:** 3740 Towle Ave. Hammond, IN 46327 **Tel:** (219) 308 - 6499

**Email:** sviveros05@gmail.com **Portfolio:** midknight92.github.io/ **Github:** github.com/MidKnight92

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/stephanie-viveros/

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Battle-At-Sea** — HTML5, CSS3, & JavaScript

- A two-player game inspired by Battleship
- Applied object-oriented programming and game logic

### **Fetch!** — *MongoDB*, *Express*, & *Node.js*

- A full-stack app to help users find and recommend dog-friendly locations in their area
- Used Places API, integrated a document-oriented database API in a RESTful architecture

### **Love Talk** — Flask & React

- A dating app, that creates user matches and allows them to send messages to one another
- Incorporated an SQLite relational database API

# **Second Chance** — *MongoDB*, *Express*, *React & Node.js*

- An adoption awareness app, that shows and matches users to dogs that are currently in need of a home
- Utilized the Petfinder API, React Router, & Reactstrap

### **SKILLS**

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | Python3 Java | C | noSQL | SQL | Git

### **EDUCATION**

## **Purdue University Calumet,** Hammond, IN — B.A. Business

2010 - 2014

### **Whiting High School,** Whiting, IN — General

2006 - 2010

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **General Assembly,** Chicago, IL — Software Engineering Fellow

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Utilized modern programming languages and technologies during a 12-week, full-time program
- Designed and built 4 web applications with emphasis on application flow, logic, and comments in a five-day stretch
- Envisioned, designed, created, and debugged applications both independently and as part of a team

## **U.S.Installers LLC,** Hammond, IN — Business Owner

July 2018 - Sep. 2019

- Developed operation plans and business strategies
- Maintained day-to-day operation
- Maintained social media accounts

# **Starbucks Coffee Company,** Schererville, IN — *Shift Supervisor*

May 2012 - present

- Lead and manage a team of 17 people
- Train and mentor new and current partners
- Resolve customer complaints
- Voted Partner of the Quarter

### **PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION**

# CS50's Introduction to Computer Science, HarvardX - edX

May 2020